<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio website for Etra Bianco</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio website for Etra Bianco</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Mac Index</title>
      <link>/blogs/bigmacindex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/bigmacindex/</guid>
      <description>In 1986 The Economist introduced The Big Mac Index, providing a unit of comparison for the cost of living in different countries and exchange rates based on the price of a Big Mac burger from McDonald’s. Burgernomics was certainly innovative and in the analysis below I dig into The Economist’s data for insights.
#importing the raw data from The Economist source_data &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;big-mac-source-data.csv&amp;quot;) historical_data &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;big-mac-historical-source-data.csv&amp;quot;) bmindex_data &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;big-mac-full-index.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brexit</title>
      <link>/blogs/brexit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/brexit/</guid>
      <description>An analysis of the Brexit Referendum The purpose of this project is to analyse the results of the 2016 Brexit vote in the UK. The data comes from Elliott Morris, who made it available through his DataCamp class on analysing election and polling data in R.
Exploratory Data Analysis Importing and inspecting the data First I import the data using read_csv() and briefly glimpse the data frame to inspect it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change</title>
      <link>/blogs/climatechange/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/climatechange/</guid>
      <description>Analysis of Temperature Anomalies The Covid-19 emergency has put a halt on, and arguably reversed, the fight for sustainability. However, the below analysis of historical temperature anomalies serves as a reminder that efforts against climate change cannot be postponed.
##Familiarizing with the data The raw data, which I import below, is sourced from NASA’s Goddard Institute for Space Studies, who recorded the Combined Land-Surface Air and Sea-Surface Water Temperature Anomalies in the Northern Hemisphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AirBnB</title>
      <link>/blogs/airbnb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 21:28:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/airbnb/</guid>
      <description>Predicting prices for AirBnBs In this project I will be analysing data about Airbnb listings in Singapore with the goal of building a model to predict the total cost for two people staying four nights in Singapore. The data is from insideairbnb.com
#importing the raw data from insideairbnb.com df_raw &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;listings.csv&amp;quot;) Inspecting and cleaning the data An initial inspection using the glimpse and skim functions above shows that the raw data consists of 7323 observations (rows) and 106 variables (columns) and includes both quantitative and qualitative information on AirBnBs in Singapore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>